gentlemansride.com 2019-12-17

# The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride

**Last Updated: 10th July 2019**

**This page is in English Only.**

The Distinguished Gentleman’s Ride is committed to safeguarding your privacy. If you have any questions or problems regarding the use of your Personal Data please contact us at privacy@gentlemansride.com

By using The Distinguished Gentleman’s Ride website or/and our services and providing your personal information, you consent to the acceptance of this Privacy Policy.

### **Collection of personal information**

We collect your personal data in the following ways:

  * When you pre-register on the website for the next event
  * When you register to ride and fundraise on our website
  * Purchase of merchandise and products
  * When you interact with us through our partners including Movember Foundation, Triumph Motorcycles, ELF Lubricants, REV’IT! Sport, Hedon Helmets, and have provided your consent for your contact details to be shared with us.
  * When you provide a donation on our website all information is collected on behalf of Movember Foundation as they are sole beneficiary and all donations are processed through the payment gateway facilitated by Movember Foundation.

When you visit our website – we gather information which might include which pages you visit most often and which services, events or information is of most interest to you.  We may also track which pages you visit when you click on links in emails from us. We use Cookies to help our website run effectively and to make improvements to ensure we are providing the best service (please see below for further information on the use of Cookies).

### **Our purposes for processing personal data**

The following sets out all of the purposes of processing of personal data The Distinguished Gentleman’s Ride undertakes, setting out how we process your personal data to achieve the purpose:

To keep you informed about The Distinguished Gentleman’s Ride events, news and other associated activities

We will ask for your email address to provide this information to you.  You will be required to ‘opt-in’ to receive these emails from us and can unsubscribe at any time by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ or ‘update email settings’ links at the bottom of emails,  or by sending an email to **privacy@gentlemansride.com.**   

To provide supporters rider profile to show fundraising activities you undertake along with money raised

We provide our supporters with a personal profile page and also a Ride Dashboard, which enables users to add blogs, update images, collect donations and share their page.

When you sign up to fundraise you will automatically receive daily updates on the amount raised and notified of any new donations made to you. 

If you wish to have your profile removed from any search engine results please email us at [privacy@gentlemansride.com](mailto:privacy@gentlemansride.com) and we will submit a deletion request.

To make a donation 

You have the option to make your donation anonymously should you choose to, so that the amount of your donation will be displayed on the participant or team’s profile but your name will not be displayed.

If you purchase products or make a donation to a participant you may provide The Distinguished Gentleman’s Ride with credit card details and other information which will allow The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride to process the transaction. Please note that The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride does not store credit card information.

We can provide you with either a personal or business receipt when you make your donation.  e will require an email address to provide this to you.

All donations made on The Distinguished Gentleman’s Ride website are facilitated through the payment gateway of Movember Foundation.

These are facilitated by the following payment gateways:

  * Adyen - [https://www.adyen.com/](https://www.adyen.com/) for all donations made in EUR, GBP, USD, AUD, CAD, NZD

To purchase The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride products or merchandise

We will require your contact details as well as payment details when you purchase The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride products or merchandise to ensure we are able to send your purchases to the correct address. We use WooCommerce, to process your orders and payments.

To advertise our work through digital ads

We use Digital Agencies to advertise the work of The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride through digital ads which is achieved using email addresses and cookies (please see below for further information about cookies).

If we send your details to Facebook for this purpose they will be hashed before they are sent, and Facebook only briefly uses the data for matching purposes then deletes it: [**https://www.facebook.com/ads/manage/customaudiences/tos.php**](https://www.facebook.com/ads/manage/customaudiences/tos.php)  

If you wish to opt out of having your details provided to Facebook or other social media platforms for the purpose of targeted advertising, please contact us at **privacy@gentlemansride.com**

To provide our supporters with fundraising packs, fulfill orders and facilitate prizes

We will require your postal address to provide you with a fundraising pack, fulfill orders purchased on the website or to help in ensuring eligible prize winners receive their items. We may also occasionally use your postal address to say thank you for your fundraising efforts.

### **Communication preferences**

Where you have agreed to receive The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride emails, The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride may use your personal information to send you emails (including marketing emails) about The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride campaign. 

This also extends to our partners The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride Foundation, whereby if you have agreed to receive The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride Foundation emails, The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride may use your personal information to send you email (including marketing emails) about the The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride Foundation.

If you are a registered participant, The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride will automatically send you a transactional email whenever there is an update on your profile or confirmation of donations you have received.

Emails that are ride critical including postponement, safety information and also important information sent from local ride hosts are listed as critical sends and you can not unsubscribe from these.

### **Disclosure of Personal Information:**

We may disclose your personal information to our suppliers or other external third parties for analytics and data analysis, for outsourcing some of the functions and services relating to the purposes for which your personal information may be processed by The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride, for storage and otherwise to enhance our Services. When we contract external services providers, we may provide them with your personal information, but only to the extent required for them to fulfil that contract, or where you would reasonably expect The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride to disclose it to a third party for a particular purpose.

Partners of The Distinguished Gentleman’s Ride that may have access to your personal information to the extent required for them to complete prize delivery obligations, the fulfilment of products or to thank riders in their respective teams include:

  * The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride Foundation
  * Triumph Motorcycles
  * ELF Lubricants
  * REV’IT! Sport
  * Hedon Helmets

We may disclose your personal information to social media platforms including, without limitation, Facebook so that the social media platforms may send you advertisements about future The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride events and initiatives and for analytics purposes.

We will not sell your personal information to other parties.

The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride will not use or disclose your personal information except in accordance with this Privacy Policy unless you have consented to the use or disclosure, or where disclosure is necessary to prevent injury to life or health, to investigate any suspected unlawful activity or where the use or disclosure is required or authorized by law.

### **Security & storage of your information:**

The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride takes reasonable steps to ensure the security of all information it collects, including that the information is protected from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. For example, your personal information may be stored and maintained in a secure cloud-based environment, which can be accessed only by authorised personnel. Some of these services are hosted by third parties located in Australia and the United States. However, as no data transmission over the internet or information stored on servers accessible through the internet can be guaranteed to be fully secure, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you send to us or receive from us online.

### **Your rights in relation to personal information:**

Your rights in relation to how organisations process your personal data have been significantly enhanced under the new General Data Protection Regulation 2018. The following sets out how The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride will ensure we meet all of these increased rights.

  1.  The right to be informed

Your right to be informed about the personal data we are processing is set out in this Privacy Policy which will be regularly reviewed to ensure you are provided with accurate information.

  2.  The right of access

You may request access to your personal information collected by The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride. Please send an email to **privacy@gentlemansride.com** and we will endeavour to respond as soon as possible and in any event within one calendar month of receiving your request.  There may be some legal or regulatory reason why access is denied or amendment refused. If this is so, we will tell you why.

  3.  The right to rectification

If you believe any of your personal information held by The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride is not accurate, complete or up-to-date, The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride will take reasonable steps to correct the information. You can make a request for rectification verbally or in writing.  To request that your personal information be corrected or updated, please send an email to **privacy@gentlemansride.com.** We will respond to your request within one calendar month.

  4.  The right to erasure

Also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’, you can now request for your personal data processed and held by us to be erased unless there is another legal requirement for us to continue to process that data, in which case this will be explained to you in response to your request. You can request for us to erase your data either verbally or in writing. We will respond to your request within one calendar month.

  5.  The right to restrict processing

Similar to your right to request the erasure of your personal data, you can request we restrict processing where you have issues with the content of the information we hold or with how we have processed your data. In these cases, we would only apply the restriction for a certain period of time while we consider your request for doing so. You can request us to restrict processing either verbally or in writing. We will respond to your request within one calendar month

  6.  The right to data portability

Where technically feasible we will endeavour to provide you with a copy of your personal data in a format that can easily be transferred to another organisation. We will respond to your request within one calendar month. Please note this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

  7.  The right to object

You have the right to object to us using your data for marketing purposes or where the processing is based on legitimate interests.

  8.  Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling

The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride does not process any personal data for automated decision making or for profiling as defined by the Regulation.

Please contact us at **privacy@gentlemansride.com** to exercise any of your rights as above.

### **Complaints**

If you have a complaint about the handling of your personal information, please send an email to **privacy@gentlemansride.com**

### **Website Advertising and Analytics**

**Pixels**

A pixel is a small amount of code on a web page or in an email notification which is used by organisations to learn how users are interacting with certain web content to help us improve our services and personalize your experience.  Pixels use you online identifiers to do this along with an anonymised version of your social media site ID. We cannot see any personal data of individual users, but the collected data are saved and processed by social media sites.  
  
You can amend your preferences or opt-out of website customised ads through Facebook below:  

**Google Analytics**

Our website uses Google Analytics who provide reports on website traffic data to help us understand usage and to ensure we continue to improve your experience when using our website.

You can amend your preferences or opt-out of Google Analytics here:

**Links to other websites**

The Distinguished Gentleman's Ride is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of any other website or service that is linked to a website, or for the privacy practices of any third party social media or other service providers that you can access through a Website. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those websites or service providers.

### **IP address**

The IP Address (Internet Protocol Address) is a unique address that computing devices such as personal computers, tablets, and smartphones use to identify itself and communicate with other devices in the IP network.

The Distinguished Gentleman’s Ride uses IP addresses to ensure our users are directed to use the right language, currency and the correct country when registering. 

We also use web log information provided through the IP address to understand any issues users may experiences while using our website to ensure a seamless service for our users. 

### **Cookies**

_What are cookies?_

Cookies are small text files that are stored in your computer’s memory and hard drive when you visit certain web pages. They are used to enable websites to function or to provide information to the owners of a website.

_Why do we use cookies?_

Cookies help us to provide customised services and information. For example, we use cookies on all our websites to collect anonymous traffic data and also to improve your experience with the Websites (e.g. to keep you logged in if you request this).  

In broad terms, we use cookies on our Websites for the following purposes:

  * _Analytical purposes_ : We use analytical cookies that allow us to recognise, measure and track visitors to our Websites. This helps us to improve and develop the way our Websites work, for example, by determining the best location, language and currency for the user.
  * For these purposes, we may store the following:
    * the name of the domain from which you accessed the internet
    * the date and time you accessed our Websites
    * the advert or internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our Websites
    * the pages you accessed while visiting our Websites
    * the device from which you accessed our Websites
    * the location from which you accessed our Websites

In addition, we use a third party service providers, to provide certain analytics services to us in connection with the operation of the website, including (without limitation) the collection and tracking of the data and information listed above. We may disclose visitor data, including personally identifiable information, to enable those third party service providers to provide such services. Such data may be sent to those third party service providers and their local overseas suppliers, where the standard of data protection may be lower than the country in which you reside.

  * _Usage preferences_ : Some of the cookies on our website are activated when visitors to our sites make a choice about their usage of the site. Our website then ‘remember’ the settings preferences of the user concerned. This allows us to tailor aspects of our sites to the individual user.
  * _Session management_ : The software that runs our website uses cookies for technical purposes needed by the internal workings of our servers and application. For instance, we use cookies to keep track of information about a user’s session and determine which options or pages to display in order for the site to function.
  * _Functional purposes_ : Functional purpose cookies store information that is needed by our applications to process and operate. For example, where requests within an application involve multiple stages, cookies are used to store the information from each stage temporarily, in order to facilitate completion of the overall request.

_Your cookie preferences_

To make full use of our website, your computer or mobile device will need to accept cookies, as our sites will not function properly without them. In addition, cookies are required in order to provide you with personalised features on our websites.

_Third party cookies_

When you visit our Websites, you may receive cookies that are set by third parties. For example, you may receive a cookie set by Google. These cookies are used for the purposes described in the “Why Do We Use Cookies?” section of this policy. We do not control the setting of these third party cookies, so we suggest you might wish to check the third party websites for more information about their use of cookies and how to manage them.

_Amending cookie preferences_

If you wish to remove cookies set by our website from your browser in the future, you may delete them. The instructions for removing cookies from your computer or mobile device depend on the operating system and web browser you use. Please note, however, that withdrawing your agreement to the use of cookies on our sites will impair the functionality of the sites.

### **Changes to this Privacy Policy:**

This privacy policy may change from time to time particularly as new rules, regulations and industry codes are introduced. Any changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted on our Website.  If we consider that the changes are material we will notify you by email.
